Guide to the Britton and Rey, Lithographers. Artotypes: Artistic homes of California [chiefly San Francisco], published in San Francisco Newsletter and Advertiser, 1887-1902
Department of Special Collections
Britton and Rey, Lithographers. Artotypes: Artistic homes of California [chiefly San Francisco], published in San Francisco Newsletter and Advertiser,
1887-1902
Mss Photo 182
Britton and Rey, Lithographers.
.5 linear feet (ca. 300 prints)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection includes artotypes of business blocks, street views, churches, schools, hotels, "bird's eye" views, and other public buildings such as an old people's home, a bath, a store, and athletic club in San Francisco. Other cities are also represented, though with far fewer illustrations, including San Jose, San Rafael, Oakland, Berkeley, Alameda, and Santa Cruz.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Early gift to the library, provenance unknown.
Scope and Content
This collection includes artotype images of private homes, public buildings, businesses, and other images of San Francisco and the Bay area from 1887 to 1902. The artotypes were published along with the San Francisco Newsletter, and are dated accordingly. While some of images spanning the chronology of the collection are not numbered in a series, the majority are organized into three distinct batches: Series I, New Series, and Panoramic Series. Those without plate numbers are organized separately, solely according to date. There are many homes depicted in artotypes labeled "Artistic Homes of California," including many homes in San Francisco prior to the 1907 earthquake and fire. Included are images of homes of many major figures in California and specifically San Francisco history, such as Charles Crocker, J.C. Flood, John D. Spreckels, Leland Stanford, and M.H. de Young. The majority of the artotypes are exterior views of homes and businesses in San Francisco, as well as views of San Francisco at large, however, other cities such as San Jose, Oakland, Alameda, San Rafael, and Belvedere are also represented. There are groups of artotypes labeled "Bird's-Eye Views of San Francisco" and "Picturesque San Francisco." These series include images of Golden Gate Park, Alcatraz Island, Chinatown, and other San Francisco landmarks. Images of Yosemite primarily constitute the series labeled "Picturesque California." Additionally, there are several artotypes of famous paintings which were exhibited in the Bay area during this period. The original collector of the series remains unknown, although it seems possible that any recipient of the San Francisco Newsletter during this period could have amassed such a collection of images.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
. 20$aBritton and Rey, Lithographers.;. 0$aArchitecture, Domestic--California--San Francisco.;. 0$aAlameda (Calif.)--History.;. 0$aBerkeley (Calif.)--History.;. 0$aCamp Waterman (Santa Cruz, Calif.);. 0$aChinatown (San Francisco, Calif.);. 0$aGolden Gate Park (San Francisco, Calif.);. 0$aOakland (Calif.)--History.;. 0$aSan Francisco (Calif.)--History.;. 0$aSan Jose (Calif.)--History.;. 0$aSan Raphael (Calif.)--History.;. 0$aSanta Cruz (Calif.)--History.;. 7$aPhotoprints.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. "Series I"
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. R.P. Ashe, corner: Van Ness Ave. & Washington St., S.F.March 19, 1887., No. 1 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Theodore F. Payne, 1409 Sutter St., S.F.March 26, 1887., No. 2 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. R.H. Pease, Jr., NW corner: Pacific Ave. & Pierce St., S.F.April 2, 1887., No. 3 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Charles Holbrook, N.W. corner: Van Ness Ave. & Washington St., S.F.April 9, 1887., No. 4 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. William Dunphy, 2122 Washington St., S.F.April 16., No. 5 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Charles Crocker, California St. between Taylor & Jones Sts., S.F.April 23, 1887., No. 6 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. J.C. Flood, NW corner: California & Mason Sts., S.F.April 30, 1887., No. 7 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Edward W. Hopkins, 2100 California St., S.F.May 7, 1887., No. 8 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Samuel G. Murphy, SE corner: Bush & Jones Sts., S.F.May 14, 1887., No. 9 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. L.L. Baker, NE corner: Washington & Franklin Sts., S.F.May 21, 1887., No. 10 (Folder 1)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Robert Sherwood, 1123 California St., S.F.May 28, 1887., No. 11 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. James Cunningham, 2518 Broadway, between Pierce & Scott Sts., S.F.June 4, 1887., No. 12 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. David N. Walter, NE corner: Sacramento St. & Van Ness Ave., S.F.June 11, 1887., No. 13 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. John D. Spreckels, SW corner: Howard & Twenty-first Sts., S.F.June 18, 1887., No. 14 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. William T. Coleman, SW corner: Taylor & Washington Sts., S.F.June 25, 1887., No. 15 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. James B. Stetson, NW corner: Van Ness Ave. & Clay St., S.F.July 2, 1887., No. 16 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Henry L. Tatum, 2525 Pacific Ave., SE corner Pierce St., S.F.July 9, 1887., No. 17 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs. Theresa Fair, NW corner: Pine & Jones Sts., S.F.July 23, 1887., No. 19 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. M.H. de Young, 1919 California St., S.F.July 30, 1887., No. 20 (Folder 2)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Charles M. Chase, NW corner: California & Scott Sts., S.F.Aug. 6, 1887., No. 21 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Charles Josselyn, SW corner: Gough & Sacramento Sts., S.F.Aug. 13, 1887., No. 22 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Nathaniel P. Cole, NW corner: Franklin & Sacramento Sts., S.F.Aug. 20, 1887., No. 23 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Dr. J.S. Potts, 259 North Third St., San Jose.Aug. 20, 1887., No. 24 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of C. T. Ryland, 431 North First St., San Jose.Aug. 27, 1887., No. 25 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Dr. W.S. Thorne, 142 North Third St., San Jose.Aug. 27, 1887., No. 26 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Senator C.H. Maddox, 549 North First St., San Jose.Sept. 3, 1887., No. 27 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Thomas S. Montgomery, 474 North First St., San Jose.Sept. 3, 1887., No. 28 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. R.B. Spence, The Alameda, San Jose.Sept. 10, 1887., No. 29 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. J.D. Spence, The Alameda, San Jose.Sept. 10, 1887., No. 30 (Folder 3)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Frank M. Stone, 2818 Howard St., S.F.Sept. 17, 1887., No. 31 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. O.A. Hale, 269 South Second St., San Jose.Sept. 17, 1887., No. 32 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. O.A. Hale, 269 South Second St., San Jose.Sept. 24, 1887., No. 32[33?] (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. P.N. Lilienthal, SW corner: Clay & Franklin Sts., S.F.Oct. 1, 1887., No. 34 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs. J.L. Watkins, 809 North 14th St., San Jose.Oct. 1, 1887., No. 35 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. James V. Coleman, NW corner: Washington & Octavia Sts., S.F.Oct. 8, 1887., No. 36 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs. M. Murphy Columbet, NW corner: 5th & William Sts., San Jose.Oct. 8, 1887., No. 37 (Folder 4)
  - Court House. Santa Clara County, San Jose.Oct. 15, 1887., No. 38 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. John I. Sabin, 1800 Pierce, corner of Pine St., S.F.Oct 15, 1887., No. 39 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Samuel T. Alexander, NW corner: 16th & Filbert Sts., Oakland.Oct 15, 1887., No. 40 (Folder 4)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. A.N. Drown, NE corner: Jackson & Pierce Sts., S.F.Oct. 22, 1887., No. 41 (Folder 5)
  - The Panorama of the Land and Naval Battles of Vicksburg, (May 22nd, 1863), "The Louisiana 'Tigers,' under the command of Gen. Pemberton, defending their works", on Exhibition at Mason & Eddy Sts., S.F.Oct. 22, 1887., No. 42 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. D.E. Allison, 2230 Broadway St., S.F.Oct. 29, 1887., No. 43 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. George W. Bowers, 2610 Jackson St., S.F.Nov. 5, 1887., No. 44 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Henry Wadsworth, 1347 Alice St., Oakland.Nov. 12, 1887., No. 45 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. William Haas, 2007 Franklin St., S.F.Nov. 19, 1887., No. 46 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. William F. Goad, NW corner: Washington & Gough Sts., S.F.Nov. 26, 1887., No. 47 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. George W. Grayson, Madison & Ninth Sts., Oakland.Dec. 3, 1887., No. 48 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. William H. Martin, 2015 Franklin St., corner of Jackson St., S.F.Dec. 10, 1887., No. 49 (Folder 5)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Henry Griffin, 1204 Harrison St., Oakland.Dec. 17, 1887., No. 50 (Folder 5)
  - The Panorama of the Land and Naval Battles of Vicksburg, (May 22nd, 1863), "The Main Confederate fort on the Mississippi shore", on Exhibition at Mason & Eddy Sts., S.F.Dec. 31, 1887., No. 51 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Lyman C. Parke, 1118 Gough St., S.F.Jan. 7, 1888., No. 52 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Ex-Governor George C. Perkins, corner: Adeline & Tenth Sts., Oakland.Jan. 14, 1888., No. 53 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Henry E. Bothin, NE corner: Van Ness Ave. & Jackson St., S.F.Jan. 21, 1888., No. 54 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of J. M. Buffington, Oakland.Jan. 28, 1888., No. 55 (Folder 6)
  - The Panorama of the Land and Naval Battles of Vicksburg, (May 22nd, 1863), "Adm. Porter's Fleet bombarding the rebel works near the shore", on Exhibition at Mason & Eddy Sts., S.F.Feb. 4, 1888., No. 56 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Jos B. Crockett, 2029 California St., S.F.Feb. 11, 1888., No. 56[57?] (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. W. Mayo Newhall, 1206 Post St., S.F.Feb. 18, 1888., No. 58 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. F.E. Brigham, NE corner: Oak & 9th Sts., Oakland.Feb. 25, 1888., No. 59 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Dr. R.I. Bowie, 2202 California St., S.F.March 3, 1888., No. 60 (Folder 6)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Wallace Everson, SW corner: Filbert & Sixteenth Sts., Oakland.March 10, 1888., No. 61 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. John Parrott, NE corner: Washington & Gough Sts., S.F.March 17, 1888., No. 62 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. John A. Wright, 2222 Washington St., S.F.March 24, 1888., No. 63 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Albert Brown, 1387 Alice St., Oakland.March 31, 1888., No. 64 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs. Henry C. Martin, NE corner: California & Taylor Sts., S.F.April 7, 1888., No. 65 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Louis Schwabacher, Clay St. near Gough St., S.F.April 14, 1888., No. 66 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Maurice Schmitt, 1501 Gough St., S.F.April 21, 1888., No. 67 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Chas. E. Green, NW corner: Fillmore & Pacific Sts., S.F.April 28, 1888., No. 68 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Eugene Meyer, NE corner: Pine & Gough Sts., S.F.May 5, 1888., No. 69 (Folder 7)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs. John Conly, 1007 Gough St., S.F.May 12, 1888., No. 70 (Folder 7)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, The History Building, 721 Market St.May 19, 1888., No. 71 (Folder 8)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, The Oriel Block, Junction of Market, Page, & Franklin Sts.May 26, 1888., No. 72 (Folder 8)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, California Pioneers' Building, Fourth St. near Market St.June 2, 1888., No. 73 (Folder 8)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Alex Boyd, NE corner: Washington & Octavia Sts., S.F.June 9, 1888., No. __ [74?] (Folder 8)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Aaron A. Adler, NW corner: Broadway & Buchanan Sts., S.F.June 16, 1888., No. 75 (Folder 8)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Phelan Building, Junction of Market & O'Farrell Sts.June 23, 1888., No. 76 (Folder 8)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. O.D. Baldwin, SE corner: Pacific & Buchanan Sts., S.F.June 30, 1888., No. 77 (Folder 8)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Montgomery St., from corner of Pine St., looking North.July 7, 1888., No. 78 (Folder 8)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Isaac E. Davis, NW corner: Pacific Ave. & Franklin St., S.F.July 14, 1888., No. 79 (Folder 8)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, South side of Market from Third to Montgomery Sts.July 21, 1888., No. 80 (Folder 8)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. H.M. Levy, NW corner: Post & Franklin Sts., S.F.July 28, 1888., No. 81 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, North side of California St. from Sansome to Montgomery Sts.Aug. 4, 1888., No. 82 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Flood Building, Market & Fourth Sts.Aug. 11, 1888., No. 83 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Union Block, Junction of Market & Pine Sts.Aug. 18, 1888., No. 84 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Maison Riche, NE corner: Geary St. & Grant Ave.Aug. 25, 1888., No. 85 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Sheldon's Block, corner: Market & First Sts.Sept. 1, 1888., No. 8_ [86?] (Folder 9)
  - Sept. 15, 1888., No. 87 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, West Side of Kearny St., looking North from Post St.Sept. 22, 1888., No. 88 (Folder 9)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. F.A. Huntington, corner: Webster & Durant Sts., Oakland.Sept. 29, 1888., No. 89 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Wells Fargo & Co.'s Bank & California Insurance Co.'s Building.Oct. 13, 1888., No. 90 (Folder 9)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, McCreery's Building, 310 Pine St.Oct. 20, 1888., No. 91 (Folder 9)
- Series 2. New Series
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Heller Building, 204-210 Sansome St.June 29, 1889., No. 1 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Fairmont Building, corner: Market, Fell, & Polk Sts.July 6, 1889., No. 2 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Maison Dorée, 217 Kearny St.July 13, 1889., No. 3 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Safe Deposit Co.'s Building, SE corner: Montgomery & California Sts.July 20, 1889., No. 4 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. W.H. Crocker, NE corner: California & Jones Sts., San FranciscoJuly 27, 1889., No. 5 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Wells, Fargo & Co.'s Building, NE corner: New Montgomery & Mission Sts.Aug. 3, 1889., No. 6 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Pacific-Union Club Building, NW corner: Post & Stockton Sts.Aug. 10, 1889., No. 7 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Redington & Co.'s Building, SE corner: Second & Stevenson Sts.Aug. 17, 1889., No. 8 (Folder 10)
  - Street Views of San Francisco, Montgomery St., from Market, looking North.Aug. 24, 1889., No. 9 (Folder 10)
  - Street Views of San Francisco, Sansome St., from Market, looking North.Aug. 31, 1889., No. 10 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Rosenthal Building, 1039-1041 Market St.Sept. 7, 1889., No. 11 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of George Wallenrod, 2618 Bryant Ave., San FranciscoSept 14, 1889., No. 12 (Folder 10)
  - Mr. Joseph MacDonough's New Yacht. (double sized artotype of painting & blue-print)Sept. 21, 1889., No. 13 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. John A. Hooper, NW corner: Clay & Laguna Sts., San FranciscoSept. 28, 1889., No. 14 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Hansford Block, NE corner: Market & Davis Sts.Oct. 5, 1889., No. 15 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. F.A. Frank, NW corner: Van Ness Ave. & Jackson St., San FranciscoOct. 12, 1889., No. 16 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. C.A. Hooper, 733 Ashbury St., between Waller & Frederick Sts., San FranciscoOct. 19, 1889., No. 17 (Folder 10)
  - "Trio Champetre" by Edouard Bernard Debat-Ponsan, Exhibited at the Paris Salon.Oct. 26, 1889., No. 18 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. W.H. Wiester, 2933 Folsom St., between 25th & 26th Sts., San FranciscoNov. 2, 1889., No. 19 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Liverpool & London & Globe Insurance Building, NE corner: California & Leidesdorff Sts.Nov. 9, 1889., No. 20 (Folder 10)
  - Senator James G. Fair's Mausoleum, Laurel Hill Cemetery, San FranciscoNov. 16, 1889., No. 21 (Folder 10)
  - "Mother's Pet" by Paul Wagner, from the S. & G. Gump Collection.Nov. 30, 1889., No. 23 (Folder 10)
  - "Pastoral Scene" by E. Debat-Ponsan, H.C., from the S. & G. Gump Collection.Dec. 7, 1889., No. 24 (Folder 10)
  - "The Argument" by Edward Kasparides, Munich, from the S. & G. Gump Collection.Dec. 14, 1889., No. 25 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, (double-sized), First National Bank Building, NW corner: Bush & Sansome Sts.Jan. 11, 1890., No. 29 (Folder 10)
  - Street Views of San Francisco, Powell St., from Market, looking North.Feb. 1, 1890., No. 32 (Folder 10)
  - Street Views of San Francisco, Grant Ave., from Market, looking North.Feb. 8, 1890., No. 33 (Folder 10)
  - Miss Lake's School for Young Ladies, corner: Sutter & Octavia Sts., San FranciscoFeb. 15, 1890., No. 34 (Folder 10)
  - "Pastoral Scene" by Julien Dupre, from the S. & G. Gump Collection.Feb. 22, 1890., No. 35 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. A.D. Moore, NE corner: Pacific Ave. & Divisadero St., San FranciscoMarch 1, 1890., No. 36 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. M.W. Murry, SE corner: Lake & Jackson Sts., Oakland.March 8, 1890., No. 37 (Folder 10)
  - Hotel Pleasanton, Mrs. M.E. Pendleton proprietor, NW corner: Jones & Sutter Sts., San FranciscoMarch 15, 1890., No. 38 (Folder 10)
  - The Strathmore, NW corner: Fulton & Larkin Sts., San FranciscoMarch 22, 1890., No. 39 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Burnett Block, 1364-1368 Market St.March 29, 1890., No. 40 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. Lyman C. Parke, SW corner: Adeline & Eighth Sts., Oakland.April 5, 1890., No. 41 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of Alameda, San Jose - double-sized, Residences of the following: April 19, 1890., No. 43 (Folder 10)
    1. Alphonse Carpentier, NW corner: San Jose Ave. & Paru St. -- 2. J.C. Siegfried, 2023 Alameda Ave. -- 3. Morton St. Station. -- 4. John Barton, NW corner: Broadway & Central Ave. -- 5. Alameda Tennis Club grounds, adjoining Morton St. Station. -- 6. Henry Mohns, Benton St. between Encinal & Central Aves. -- 7. Columbus Bartlett, St. Charles St. near Bay. -- 8. E.H. Miller, Jr., Grand St. & Encinal Ave.
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs. E.W. Goggin, 1913 Van Ness Ave., San FranciscoApril 26, 1890., No. 44 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco, Kohler & Frohling's Wine Vaults, SW corner: Folsom & Second Sts.May 3, 1890., No. 45 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - von Schroeder Dwellings, West side of Howard St., between 22nd & 23rd Sts., San FranciscoMay 10, 1890., No. 46 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of J.S. Merrill, 534 Twenty-fifth St., Oakland.May 17, 1890., No. 47 (Folder 10)
  - New Grounds of the Olympic Athletic Club - double sizedMay 24, 1890., No. 48 (Folder 10)
    1. Entrance -- 2. Hand Ball Court -- 3. The Finish -- 4. Club House -- 5. Reporters' Stand -- 6. The Start -- 7. Speed Track and Cinder Path.
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mr. I.L. Requa, Piedmont.May 31, 1890., No. 49 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Mrs Theresa Fair, with Supper Marquee, as arranged for the Fair-Oelrichs Wedding, 6/3/90.June 7, 1890., No. 50 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco - double-sized, The General Keys Building, 13-17 Stockton St., and 107-109 O'Farrell St.June 14, 1890., No. 51 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California, Selected Villas in Alameda, quadruple-sized, Residences and other views as follows:June 21, 1890., No. 52 (Folder 10)
    1. D. Herschfield, Railroad Ave. & Morton St. -- 2. S. Haslett, 2501 Central Ave. -- 3. John Gale, Regent St., between Central & Euclid Aves. -- 4. E.A. Vinig, 2014 Alameda Ave. -- 5. F.H. Kellogg, 1958 Santa Clara Ave. -- 6. H.P. Moreal, Park St. -- 7. R.H. Swayne, 2326 Alameda Ave. -- 8. San Francisco Geissler, Morton St., near San Antonia Ave. -- 9. A. Leonard, SW corner: Union St. & San Antonia Ave. -- 10. View of Alameda, from Water Works Tower, looking West. -- 11. H.B. Smith, corner: Central Ave. & Benton St. -- 12. W. Wilson, corner: Lafayette St. & Alameda Ave. -- 13. W.A. Bissell, corner: Alameda Ave. & Union St. -- 14. O.A. Lunt, corner: Central Ave. & Willow St. -- 15. J.A. Remmell, St. Charles St., near the Bay. -- 16. G.W. Bennett, corner: Central Ave. & Paru St. -- 17. T.G. Daniels, corner: Chestnut St. & Encinal Ave. -- 18. F. Wild, corner: Morton St. & Encinal Ave. -- 19. C.E. Naylor, 1439 Morton St. -- 20. Chestnut Street Station. -- 21. A. Victor, East Side Paru St., near San Antonia Ave. -- 22. C.E. Dwinelle, Weber St., near the Bay.
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of Judge J.A. Waymire, corner: Walnut St. & Buena Vista Ave., Alameda.June 28, 1890., No. 53 (Folder 10)
  - Hotel Rafael - San Rafael, 1. Entrance to Grounds, 2. Garden Walk, 3. Cottages, 4. Club House, 5. View in the Grounds, 6. Lawn Tennis Court, 7. Water Tower & Observatory, 8. The Hotel. July 4, 1890., No. 54 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco - Rosenbaum Building, NE corner: Front & California Sts.July 12, 1890., No. 55 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco - New Chronicle Building, corner: Market & Kearny Sts. July 19, 1890., No. 56 (Folder 10)
  - Artistic Homes of California - Residence of H.M.A. Miller, 1111 Pine St., San Francisco July 26, 1890., No. 57 (Folder 10)
  - Business Blocks of San Francisco - Lachman's Block, SW corner: Market & Fremont Sts.Aug. 2, 1890., No. 58 (Folder 10)
  - Old People's Home, SW corner: Pierce & Pine Sts., San FranciscoAug. 9, 1890., No. 59 (Folder 10)